10 years later... A new generation of scanners, Born with
powers so terrifying, it's beyond their control!
Scanners II: The New Order is a horror, science fiction,
action film directed by Christian Duguay.
A breed of humans with dangerously powerful telepathic abilities -- the scanners -- are being recruited
by a corrupt police commander, John Forrester, in his crusade to take over the city.
David Kellum, played by David Hewlett.
Julie Vale, played by Deborah Raffin.
Commander John Forrester, played by Yvan Ponton.
Alice Leonardo, played by Isabelle Mejias.
Doctor Morse, played by Tom Butler.
Peter Drak, played by Raoul Max Trujillo.
Scanners II: The New Order is a 1991 Canadian science fiction thriller film.
It is a sequel to the 1981 feature film Scanners with a different cast, starring
David Hewlett, Deborah Raffin, Raoul Trujillo, and Yvan Ponton.
It was written by B.
Nelson and directed by Christian Duguay.
The plot involves a crooked police commissioner (Ponton) who schemes to gain control of a major city by
manipulating Scanners (persons born with telepathic and telekinetic abilities) to do his bidding.
The film was released direct-to-video.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.